Their Empire. His Kingdom.
Son of God is a drama film directed by Christopher Spencer.
In the Holy Land, the Roman occupation has produced a cauldron of oppression,
anxiety and excessive taxes levied upon the Jewish people.
Fearing the wrath of Roman governor Pontius Pilate , Jewish high
priest Caiaphas tries to keep control of his people.
That control is threatened when Jesus arrives in Jerusalem,
performing miracles and spreading messages of love and hope.
Those who fear that Jesus will inspire a revolution decide that he must die.
Jesus, played by Diogo Morgado.
Mary, Mother of Jesus, played by Roma Downey.
Pilate, played by Greg Hicks.
Caiaphas, played by Adrian Schiller.
Peter, played by Darwin Shaw.
John, played by Sebastian Knapp.
Son of God is a 2014 American epic biblical film directed by Christopher
Spencer, and produced by Mark Burnett and Roma Downey.
The film retells the life of Jesus Christ and is an adaptation of the miniseries The Bible, which aired in March
2013 on the History channel, and immediately following the movie begins another TV series called A.D.
The Bible Continues.
The film stars Diogo Morgado, Greg Hicks, Adrian Schiller, Darwin Shaw, Sebastian Knapp, Joe
Wredden, Simon Kunz, Paul Marc Davis, Matthew Gravelle, Amber Rose Revah, and Roma Downey.
The film was released in the United States and Canada on February 28, 2014.
The film received positive reviews from Christian publications but generally
negative reviews from mainstream critics, who called it "too dull".
Despite this, the film was a box office success, grossing $70 million against a budget of $22
million, making it the seventh-highest grossing Christian film of all time.
The film explores themes of christianity,
crucifixion, bible, biography, resurrection.
The tone is emotional.